<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fiction on ninjaduck</title>
    <link>http://ninjaducks.in/tags/fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fiction on ninjaduck</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2014 13:35:54 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://ninjaducks.in/tags/fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I read Fiction</title>
      <link>http://ninjaducks.in/why-i-read-fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2014 13:35:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ninjaducks.in/why-i-read-fiction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been reading fiction since I was 10. By the age of 12, I was hooked so much into it that I read nothing but fiction. Now, reading has turned into a habit. I always read for about half and hour almost ever night before going to sleep, more if I have time and mostly it is fiction. Over the time, my parents have relentlessly nagged at me for reading fiction. What good possibly come out of my reading made up stories about made up people in sometimes made up places and most of the times completely unrelated time periods? Am I simply wasting my time by reading fiction?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schools encourage reading novels. I was fortunate enough to go to a school which had a huge library which was stacked with all sort of books in neatly arranged racks. All the teachers in my school encouraged reading. Once, the librarian even forced us to read a novel of their choice. She gave it to us as a homework and we were supposed to tell her the brief story of our novel the next week. She went as far as to punish those who did not read it. Why would anyone make such a fuss about reading if it serves no purpose?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course reading increases vocabulary and command at a language and many a times increase our knowledge, makes you more creative. But for me these are just side-effects. Reading conforms to other things. I read many a times for escapism, sometimes for the simple pleasure of reading, sometimes for nostalgia. Whether I am reading about the poverty of Francie Nolan in A Tree Grows In Brooklyn or the affairs of the rich in early 19th century England in Pride &amp;amp; Prejudice, it is to escape the real world with all its worries and people and root for the fictional characters. As &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/author/show/6984795.Non_Pratt&#34;&gt;Non Pratt&lt;/a&gt; so eloquently writes in her article for The Guardian on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/childrens-books-site/2014/jun/10/adults-reading-ya-kids-teen-fiction-non-pratt&#34;&gt;adult&amp;rsquo;s reading children&amp;rsquo;s book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, reading is an end in itself&amp;hellip;. I read because my soul sings when I&amp;rsquo;m lost in a good narrative or caught up with characters I wish were real. I read because I love reading&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many times at the end of the day I pick up and read an old novel like Harry Potter or Tom Sawyer just to reminiscence the old days when I read them originally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though these things are enough to motivate me to read, reading fiction also has a much deeper effect. According to Neil Gaiman in his lecture for The Reading Agency, reading builds empathy, by forcing us to imagine the situation from the words we read which is different than watching a TV or film. Empathy makes us broad minded, allows us to function as more than self-obsessed individuals. I recommend everyone to watch his lecture on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yNIUWv9_ZH0&#34;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yNIUWv9_ZH0&lt;/a&gt; or read its summary on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/books/2013/oct/15/neil-gaiman-future-libraries-reading-daydreaming&#34;&gt;http://www.theguardian.com/books/2013/oct/15/neil-gaiman-future-libraries-reading-daydreaming&lt;/a&gt;. It makes you feel good about reading fiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a culture like mine where there is scarcity of everything, and everybody is bent upon, as Aravind Adiga puts it in The White Tiger, breaking out of the rooster coop, most people don&amp;rsquo;t give much value to reading just for pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, a quote by George R.R. Martin to encourage all the readers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reader lives a thousand lives before he dies. The man who never reads lives only once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I like &#39;The Book Thief&#39;</title>
      <link>http://ninjaducks.in/why-i-like-the-book-thief/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 13:35:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ninjaducks.in/why-i-like-the-book-thief/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had read The Book Thief book in November and have been trying to write a review ever since but I could never finds words enough to describe it. It was the greatest reading experience I have ever had. Set in the Nazi Germany and narrated by Death(the Grim Reaper), it is the story of the life of a young girl Liesel Meminger - the book thief. The book deftly highlights the themes of destruction and loss of life in war, the viciousness of the Nazi propaganda and the power of words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;pull-right&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://d202m5krfqbpi5.cloudfront.net/books/1390053681l/19063.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few chapters into the book, the narrator declares&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mystery bores me. It chores me. I know what happens and so do you. It’s the machinations that wheel us there that aggravate, perplex, interest, and astound me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only the book does not have suspense but it derides it by telling the events in advance. Even though I love the thrill of not knowing something in advance, in this particular instance, it was this characteristic of the novel which made it special. The revelations about the future of the story help the reader to think about the event, relate it to all that is currently happening, and have a greater impact when it actually occurs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book never needs suspense to build upon. It has such deep characters, such rich descriptions, such an involving story and such a powerful narration that it never during the 500 pages does it loose its charm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author markedly highlights the Holocaust through Max - a Jew, on the run from the authorities, who is covertly sheltered by Liesel&amp;rsquo;s family, and the countless crimes committed by the Nazi party against the Jews. But above all, the narrator Death has the most memorable impact on me with his keen observations and admiration for humans. Death in the book in many ways seems more living than dead. Death can feel joy, disappointment and can get depressed. A few of my favorite lines by Death are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to explain that I am constantly overestimating and underestimating the human race - that rarely do I even simply estimate it. I wanted to ask her how the same thing could be so ugly and so glorious, and its words and stories so damning and brilliant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am haunted by humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read it. You may or may not like it but it is definitely worth a try.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>