<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cinephilia on ninjaduck</title>
    <link>http://www.ninjaducks.in/categories/cinephilia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cinephilia on ninjaduck</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 13:35:54 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.ninjaducks.in/categories/cinephilia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>La La Land - The Ending</title>
      <link>http://www.ninjaducks.in/movies/la-la-land/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 13:35:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ninjaducks.in/movies/la-la-land/</guid>
      <description>La La Land is a remarkable movie in many ways. Even its name is a pun upon the city of L.A., the home of Hollywood, where the movie is set. It is a musical love story of Mia - a struggling actress and Sebastian - a jazz pianist, talented but unsuccessful.
 I feel that its the ending of the movie that gives it its true character. When both of them have achieved their creative ambitions- Mia is a successful actress and is married with a kid, Sebastian owns a jazz bar of his own, they meet again when Mia happens to go to Sebastian&amp;rsquo;s jazz club with her husband.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie Review – Akira(1988)</title>
      <link>http://www.ninjaducks.in/movies/akira-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 13:35:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ninjaducks.in/movies/akira-review/</guid>
      <description>Akira is a quintessential cyberpunk movie. What is cyberpunk? It is this cool subgenre of Science Fiction which is characterized by a post-apocalyptic dystopian society and advanced technology. Common cyberpunk themes often deal with the role of advanced technology like artificial intelligence in human lives, the moral and philosophical issues they raise. It often raises the question – “What does it mean to be human?”. Many films adopt a film-noir style and have a dark, skeptical tone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie Review – J.S.A.: Joint Security Area</title>
      <link>http://www.ninjaducks.in/movies/jsa-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 13:35:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ninjaducks.in/movies/jsa-review/</guid>
      <description>J.S.A.: Joint Security Area is a South Korean movie directed by the amazing Park Chan Wook. JSA was his first successful movie both critically and commercially. Based on the novel &amp;ldquo;DMZ&amp;rdquo; by Park Sang-yeon, J.S.A tells the story of an incident that happened on the DMZ (Demilitarized Zone) between North and South Korea which involved death of two North Korean soldiers, presumably by a South Korean soldier.
A bit of history to explain the hostility between North and South Korea – At the end of World War two, after the surrender of Japanese forces, Korea was divided into two states, with the North under Soviet occupation and the South under U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anime Binge Watch - Erased</title>
      <link>http://www.ninjaducks.in/movies/erased-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 13:35:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ninjaducks.in/movies/erased-review/</guid>
      <description>After finishing my M.Tech thesis, I had some free time on my hands. It was an ideal situation to satiate my gluttonous appetite for some movies/tv. This time I chose to watch some long outstanding anime. Despite animes having some excellent stroylines and amazing characters, I had been withholding the urge to watch them for a long time due their addictive/bingeworthy nature.
 The first anime I binge-watched was Boku dake ga Inai Machi (The Town Where Only I am Missing) also known as Erased in English.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie Review - Captain Phillips</title>
      <link>http://www.ninjaducks.in/movies/movie-review-captain-philips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 13:35:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.ninjaducks.in/movies/movie-review-captain-philips/</guid>
      <description>If you are gonna shoot somebody, you shoot me. I&amp;rsquo;m the captain, not them.
  In the direst of situations when one of the pirates has a gun cocked to a crew-member&amp;rsquo;s head threatening to kill him if the captain did not reveal where the other crew members were hiding, he had the guts to say this.
The story is based on the hijacking of an american ship - MV Maersk Alabama by Somali pirate in 2009.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>